[
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question_text": "What are the null and alternative hypotheses?",
        "answers": [
            "Null hypothesis: nothing happened; Alternative hypothesis: under the same conditions, something did happen the second time.",
            "Null hypothesis: there is no observable effect in the population; Alternative hypothesis: there is an observable effect in the population.",
            "Null hypothesis: there is no explanation for a given phenomenon; Alternative hypothesis: there is an explanation."
        ],
        "answer": "Null hypothesis: there is no observable effect in the population; Alternative hypothesis: there is an observable effect in the population.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655636922.8880987,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "question_text": "How do you calculate the correlation, r, between two variables, x & y? (x_bar is the mean for x, and likewise y_bar for y)",
        "answers": [
            "r = (1/n) * \u2211 [((x_i - x_bar)/\u03c3_x) * ((y_i - y_bar)/\u03c3_y)]",
            "r = (1/n) * \u2211 [((x_i + x_bar)/\u03c3_x) + ((y_i + y_bar)/\u03c3_y)]",
            "r = (n) * \u2211 [((x_i - x_bar)/ \u03c3_x) + ((y_i - y_bar)/\u03c3_y)]"
        ],
        "answer": "r = (1/n) * \u2211 [((x_i - x_bar)/\u03c3_x) * ((y_i - y_bar)/\u03c3_y)]",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 2,
        "last_asked": 1655636949.8024523,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question_text": "When can we reject the null hypothesis?",
        "answers": [
            "When p > \u03b1.",
            "When p = \u03b1.",
            "When p \u2264 \u03b1."
        ],
        "answer": "When p \u2264 \u03b1.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1655636957.685089,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question_text": "What is the Open-Closed Principle?",
        "answers": [
            "Entities should be open for extension, but closed for modification.",
            "All entities should have get methods for all fields.",
            "All objects should be closed to save memory."
        ],
        "answer": "Entities should be open for extension, but closed for modification.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1655956346.9228232,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question_text": "Let A, B \u2208 F be any two events. What event is A \u222a B?",
        "answers": [
            "Either event A occurs, or B occurs, but not both (Exclusive Or).",
            "The event that neither A nor B occur.",
            "The event A occurs, or B occurs, or they both occur (Inclusive Or)."
        ],
        "answer": "The event A occurs, or B occurs, or they both occur (Inclusive Or).",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655956583.0136547,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question_text": "What does variance measure?\n (\u03a3 (x_i - \u00b5)^2)/n ",
        "answers": [
            "It measures how close an individual data point is from the mean.",
            "It measures the average change between data points.",
            "It measures the average distance of all data points from the mean."
        ],
        "answer": "It measures the average distance of all data points from the mean.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655956593.4081397,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "question_text": "What is the Central Limit Theorem wrt to Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "Randomly selected samples will exhibit identical variances to the population variance.",
            "The arithmetic average of the mean, median, and mode provide an upper limit to the standard deviations of randomly selected samples from a given population.",
            "Regardless of population distribution, the distribution of randomly selected sample means will have a normal distribution centered around the population mean."
        ],
        "answer": "Regardless of population distribution, the distribution of randomly selected sample means will have a normal distribution centered around the population mean.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1655956613.9252446,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question_text": "Let A, B \u2208 F be any two events. What event is A complement?",
        "answers": [
            "B - A, Either event A occurs, or B occurs, but not both.",
            "S - A, the event that A does not occur.",
            "F - A, The event that neither A nor B occur."
        ],
        "answer": "S - A, the event that A does not occur.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655956623.3345668,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question_text": "What is a 'Confidence Interval' wrt to Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "A range of two standard deviations.",
            "A measure of distance from the mode.",
            "The middle 90% range of a dataset."
        ],
        "answer": "The middle 90% range of a dataset.",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1655956637.7471528,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question_text": "What does the 'O' in S.O.L.I.D. stand for?",
        "answers": [
            "Open-Closed Principle",
            "Overuse Principle",
            "Only Once Principle"
        ],
        "answer": "Open-Closed Principle",
        "n_times_asked": 7,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 7,
        "last_asked": 1655956640.9087725,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question_text": "What is 'Bootstrapping' wrt to Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "The process of creating new samples by choosing n-1 values from the original sample of size n.",
            "The process of creating new samples by choosing n values from the original sample of size n uniformly and with replacement.",
            "The process of creating new samples by choosing a random number of values from the original sample of size n."
        ],
        "answer": "The process of creating new samples by choosing n values from the original sample of size n uniformly and with replacement.",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1655956659.0891807,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question_text": "What is statistical power?",
        "answers": [
            "It is the metric used to determine the author's credibility.",
            "It is the likelihood of a significance test detecting an effect when there is one (True Positive). It is mainly influenced by sample size, effect size, and significance level.",
            "It is the probability of avoiding a Type I error (False Positive)."
        ],
        "answer": "It is the likelihood of a significance test detecting an effect when there is one (True Positive). It is mainly influenced by sample size, effect size, and significance level.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655956669.6456428,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question_text": "If a sample space S is finite, then |S| = N. What is the magnitude of F? [F = { A | A \u2286 S }]",
        "answers": [
            "2^S.",
            "2^F.",
            "2^N."
        ],
        "answer": "2^N.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1655956692.453713,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question_text": "What does the 'L' in S.O.L.I.D. stand for?",
        "answers": [
            "Liskov Substitution Principle",
            "Last In Principle",
            "Later Principle"
        ],
        "answer": "Liskov Substitution Principle",
        "n_times_asked": 7,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 7,
        "last_asked": 1656234231.2490485,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question_text": "Let A, B \u2208 F be any two events. What event is A \u2229 B? (Also written AB)",
        "answers": [
            "Either event A occurs, or B occurs, but not both.",
            "The event that neither A nor B occur.",
            "Both events A and B occur."
        ],
        "answer": "Both events A and B occur.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1656234254.6404085,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question_text": "What is Modus Ponens?",
        "answers": [
            "Denying the consequent: P -> Q AND ~Q, thus ~P.",
            "Inversion: P -> Q AND Q -> P, thus Q AND P.",
            "Affirming the antecedent: P -> Q AND P, thus Q."
        ],
        "answer": "Affirming the antecedent: P -> Q AND P, thus Q.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1656234271.2800097,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "logic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question_text": "What does the 'S' in S.O.L.I.D. stand for?",
        "answers": [
            "Simplicity is Key",
            "Single Responsibility Principle",
            "Save Frequently"
        ],
        "answer": "Single Responsibility Principle",
        "n_times_asked": 7,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 7,
        "last_asked": 1656234283.3463273,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "question_text": "What are standard deviation and standard error?",
        "answers": [
            "Standard deviation measures average dispersion from mean; standard error measures accuracy of standard deviation.",
            "Standard deviation measures average dispersion from mean; standard error measures average dispersion from median.",
            "Standard error is the standard deviation of the sample means."
        ],
        "answer": "Standard error is the standard deviation of the sample means.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656234332.0900674,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Ionian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "W-W-H-W-W-W-H",
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W"
        ],
        "answer": "W-W-H-W-W-W-H",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656234347.1507044,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question_text": "What qualifies as an outlier wrt Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "Anything less than the first quartile - (1.5 x IQR) or greater than the third quartile + (1.5 x IQR). Extreme outliers are 3 x IQR.",
            "Anything below the first quartile and above the third quartile.",
            "Anything one standard deviation from the mean in either direction."
        ],
        "answer": "Anything less than the first quartile - (1.5 x IQR) or greater than the third quartile + (1.5 x IQR). Extreme outliers are 3 x IQR.",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656234362.548552,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Lydian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "W-W-W-H-W-W-H",
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W"
        ],
        "answer": "W-W-W-H-W-W-H",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656234387.4984643,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question_text": "What is Bayes' Theorem?",
        "answers": [
            "P(A) = P(A|B) * P(B|A)/P(B); Prior = Posterior * Likelihood/Marginal",
            "P(B|A) = P(A) * P(A|B)/P(B); Likelihood = Prior * Posterior/Marginal",
            "P(A|B) = P(A) * P(B|A)/P(B); Posterior = Prior * Likelihood/Marginal"
        ],
        "answer": "P(A|B) = P(A) * P(B|A)/P(B); Posterior = Prior * Likelihood/Marginal",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1656234402.6917145,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "machine learning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question_text": "If an event A is defined as any subset of the sample space S, then what are the definitions of S, \u00d8, and F? [F = { A | A \u2286 S }]",
        "answers": [
            "The impossible event, the class of all possible events, the sure event.",
            "The sure event, the impossible event, the class of all possible events.",
            "The sure event, the class of all possible events, the impossible event."
        ],
        "answer": "The sure event, the impossible event, the class of all possible events.",
        "n_times_asked": 4,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 4,
        "last_asked": 1656234434.116227,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "question_text": "If there are 3 flavors of ice cream and 5 toppings, then how many different combinations of ice cream and toppings are there?",
        "answers": [
            "15",
            "23",
            "8"
        ],
        "answer": "15",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656251549.9017813,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "counting",
            "statistics"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question_text": "What is the Interface Segregation Principle?",
        "answers": [
            "Interfaces should define implementation details.",
            "No two interfaces should ever overlap.",
            "Interfaces should be narrow, not wide."
        ],
        "answer": "Interfaces should be narrow, not wide.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1656251568.0272992,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Phrygian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "H-W-W-W-H-W-W",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W",
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H"
        ],
        "answer": "H-W-W-W-H-W-W",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656251581.5763829,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question_text": "If a test for a disease D has a sensitivity of 0.95 (Test Positive given D, or P(TP|D)), and a specificity of 0.92 (Test Negative given not D, or P(TPc|Dc) and the probability of actually having the disease is P(D) = 0.05 (i.e., only 5% of the population has the disease), then what are the chances a person who tests positive actually has the disease: P(D|TP)?\n Hint: Bayes' Rule",
        "answers": [
            "0.2345",
            "0.3846",
            "0.1656"
        ],
        "answer": "0.3846",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656251909.3645978,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Dorian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W",
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "W-H-W-W-W-H-W"
        ],
        "answer": "W-H-W-W-W-H-W",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656251922.7340653,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "question_text": "Matrices A and B are respectively defined thusly:\n[1 2 3] [1 2]\n[4 5 6] [3 4]\n        [5 6]\nWhat is the value of (1,1) where (r,c) for the dot product of A x B?",
        "answers": [
            "28",
            "22",
            "49"
        ],
        "answer": "22",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656251937.6232955,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "question_text": "Matrices A and B are respectively defined thusly:\n[1 2 3] [1 2]\n[4 5 6] [3 4]\n        [5 6]\nWhat is the value of (1,2) where (r,c) for the dot product of A x B?",
        "answers": [
            "28",
            "22",
            "49"
        ],
        "answer": "28",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656251948.5651765,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "question_text": "Matrices A and B are respectively defined thusly:\n[1 2 3] [1 2]\n[4 5 6] [3 4]\n        [5 6]\nWhat is the value of (2,1) where (r,c) for the dot product of A x B?",
        "answers": [
            "22",
            "28",
            "49"
        ],
        "answer": "49",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656251974.607503,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "question_text": "Matrices A and B are respectively defined thusly:\n[1 2 3] [1 2]\n[4 5 6] [3 4]\n        [5 6]\nWhat is the value of (2,2) where (r,c) for the dot product of A x B?",
        "answers": [
            "49",
            "28",
            "64"
        ],
        "answer": "64",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656251990.0867717,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question_text": "What is the difference between a 'Statistic' and a 'Parameter' wrt Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "A parameter is a representative property of a sample; whereas, a statistic describes the population as a whole.",
            "A statistic represents a property of a population sample; whereas, a parameter is a numerical characteristic of a whole population that is estimated by a statistic.",
            "A parameter are the variables used to generalize a statistic."
        ],
        "answer": "A statistic represents a property of a population sample; whereas, a parameter is a numerical characteristic of a whole population that is estimated by a statistic.",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656252010.098079,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Aeolian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "W-H-W-W-H-W-W",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W"
        ],
        "answer": "W-H-W-W-H-W-W",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656987806.6161373,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "question_text": "What is a z-score wrt Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "A z-score is the distance between two standard deviations and the mode.",
            "A z-score is the average standard deviation for all observations.",
            "A z-score is the number of standard deviations an observation is from the mean."
        ],
        "answer": "A z-score is the number of standard deviations an observation is from the mean.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656987820.0000865,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question_text": "When is 'Resampling' to be avoided wrt Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "When there are less than 1000 datapoints.",
            "When there is a very narrow Interquartile Range.",
            "When the data exhibit serial dependence (e.g., in a musical melody)."
        ],
        "answer": "When the data exhibit serial dependence (e.g., in a musical melody).",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656987841.278838,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question_text": "What is the name of the paradox that states:\nFor numbers a, b, c, d, A, B, C, & D\nA/B > a/b and C/D > c/d does NOT imply that (A+C)/(B+D) > (a+c)/(b+d)\ne.g., 81/87 > 234/270 and 192/263 > 55/80, but NOT 273/350 > 289/350?",
        "answers": [
            "Derrier's Paradox.",
            "Simpson's Paradox.",
            "Markov's Paradox."
        ],
        "answer": "Simpson's Paradox.",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656987886.5790932,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question_text": "What is the Liskov Substitution Principle?",
        "answers": [
            "Every subclass should function as a substitute for their base class.",
            "Subclasses should never be declared as types of their base class",
            "Subclasses should be identical to their base class."
        ],
        "answer": "Every subclass should function as a substitute for their base class.",
        "n_times_asked": 7,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 7,
        "last_asked": 1656987902.3515992,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question_text": "What does the 'I' in S.O.L.I.D. stand for?",
        "answers": [
            "Inversion of Control",
            "Interest First",
            "Interface Segregation Principle"
        ],
        "answer": "Interface Segregation Principle",
        "n_times_asked": 7,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 7,
        "last_asked": 1656987915.345236,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "question_text": "How do you calculate expected value, where two events, A & B, are possible, and they have a payoff of X & Y, respectively?\nAssume A \u222a B = S, and thus, |S| = |A \u222a B| = N",
        "answers": [
            "ev = [(P(A) * X) + (P(B) * Y)] / N",
            "ev = (P(A) * X/N) * (P(B) * Y/N)",
            "ev = 1/N * [(P(A) * Y) + (P(B) * X)]"
        ],
        "answer": "ev = [(P(A) * X) + (P(B) * Y)] / N",
        "n_times_asked": 2,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 2,
        "last_asked": 1656987966.5324433,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "question_text": "What is the Empirical Rule wrt Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "For a normal distribution, 65% of the data will be within 1 standard deviation from the mean; 95% will be within 2 standard deviations; and 99.7% will be within 3 standard deviations.",
            "For a binomial distribution, 65% of the data will be within 1 standard deviation from the mean; 95% will be within 2 standard deviations; and 99.7% will be within 3 standard deviations.",
            "For a gaussian distribution, 65% of the data will be within 3 standard deviations from the mean; 95% will be within 2 standard deviations; and 99.7% will be within 1 standard deviation."
        ],
        "answer": "For a normal distribution, 65% of the data will be within 1 standard deviation from the mean; 95% will be within 2 standard deviations; and 99.7% will be within 3 standard deviations.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656987980.1002765,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Locrian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W",
            "H-W-W-H-W-W-W"
        ],
        "answer": "H-W-W-H-W-W-W",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1656987992.2145565,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "question_text": "How does one calculate the dot product or inner product of two vectors wrt Linear Algebra?",
        "answers": [
            "For vectors A and B, where A = (a,b,c) and B = (x,y,z), the dot product A * B = (ax,by,cz).",
            "For vectors A and B, where A = (a,b,c) and B = (x,y,z), the dot product A * B = ax + by + cz.",
            "For vectors A and B, where A = (a,b,c) and B = (x,y,z), the dot product A * B = ax * by * cz."
        ],
        "answer": "For vectors A and B, where A = (a,b,c) and B = (x,y,z), the dot product A * B = ax + by + cz.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1656988013.8120205,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "question_text": "When are two vectors said to be orthogonal (perpendicular) to one another wrt Linear Algebra?",
        "answers": [
            "When their dot product equals 0.",
            "When they have a different number of components (e.g., A=(a,b), B=(w,x,y,z)).",
            "When they point in opposite directions."
        ],
        "answer": "When their dot product equals 0.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1657111343.4271004,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "linear algebra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question_text": "What is the Dependency Inversion Principle?",
        "answers": [
            "Software should have zero dependencies.",
            "Entities must depend on abstractions (interfaces), not concretions (implementations).",
            "The user should not depend on the software dev to fix their problems."
        ],
        "answer": "Entities must depend on abstractions (interfaces), not concretions (implementations).",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1657111380.5114114,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "question_text": "How many different ways are there to arrange the elements in a set N (i.e., how many permutations)?",
        "answers": [
            "N!.",
            "Nn.",
            "N^n."
        ],
        "answer": "N!.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1657111412.4656627,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "combinatorics",
            "probability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question_text": "What are Type I and Type II errors?",
        "answers": [
            "False Positive, Data Collection error, respectively.",
            "False Positive, False Negative, respectively.",
            "False Negative, False Positive, respectively."
        ],
        "answer": "False Positive, False Negative, respectively.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657111421.9179432,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question_text": "What is the contrapositive?",
        "answers": [
            "P -> Q, thus ~Q -> P.",
            "P -> Q, thus ~P -> ~Q.",
            "P -> Q, thus ~Q -> ~P."
        ],
        "answer": "P -> Q, thus ~Q -> ~P.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1657111439.010898,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "logic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "question_text": "Defined in whole (W) and half (H) steps, what is the proper sequence of steps from the tonic for the Mixolydian mode?",
        "answers": [
            "W-H-H-W-W-W-H",
            "W-W-H-W-W-H-W",
            "H-W-H-W-W-W-W"
        ],
        "answer": "W-W-H-W-W-H-W",
        "n_times_asked": 3,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 3,
        "last_asked": 1657111468.6108792,
        "skills": [
            508
        ],
        "tags": [
            "music",
            "church modes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question_text": "What is currying wrt functions?",
        "answers": [
            "It is the technique whereby you pass a single vector as a parameter instead of all the elements of said vectors as individual parameters.",
            "It is the technique of taking several functions a coalescing them into a single function.",
            "It is the technique of converting a function that takes multiple arguments into a sequence of functions that each takes a single argument."
        ],
        "answer": "It is the technique of converting a function that takes multiple arguments into a sequence of functions that each takes a single argument.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1657111497.6450164,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "functional programming"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question_text": "What does the 'D' in S.O.L.I.D. stand for?",
        "answers": [
            "Dependency Inversion Principle",
            "Dual-Use Principle",
            "Denial of Service"
        ],
        "answer": "Dependency Inversion Principle",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1657111507.403898,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "software engineering",
            "programming",
            "technocraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "question_text": "Which correlation is a number between -1 and 1 that indicates both the strength and sign of the association between two variables?",
        "answers": [
            "Pearson correlation.",
            "Schnier correlation.",
            "Laplace correlation."
        ],
        "answer": "Pearson correlation.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1657111519.4381032,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "question_text": "How many outcomes are possible when an element is selected from a set N with replacement n times?",
        "answers": [
            "Nn.",
            "N^n.",
            "N!."
        ],
        "answer": "N^n.",
        "n_times_asked": 1,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 1,
        "last_asked": 1657111538.8377624,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "combinatorics",
            "probability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question_text": "What is the difference between Descriptive Statistics and Inferential Statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "Descriptive Statistics show what the data are; Inferential Statistics show what the data mean.",
            "Descriptive Statistics describe how to do Inferential Statistics.",
            "Descriptive Statistics cannot be done without Inferential Statistics."
        ],
        "answer": "Descriptive Statistics show what the data are; Inferential Statistics show what the data mean.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657115578.0355487,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "question_text": "When are two events statistically independent? P(A \u2229 B) = P(A) * P(B)",
        "answers": [
            "When two events cannot both possibly happen.",
            "When two events do not depend on a third event for their occurrence.",
            "When the events can happen in any order, and the first event does not affect the probability of the second event occurring."
        ],
        "answer": "When the events can happen in any order, and the first event does not affect the probability of the second event occurring.",
        "n_times_asked": 2,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 2,
        "last_asked": 1657115590.8471425,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question_text": "What are the three measures of central tendency in statistics?",
        "answers": [
            "Median, Mode, Meridian",
            "Mode, Median, Mean",
            "Mode, Median, Meridian"
        ],
        "answer": "Mode, Median, Mean",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657115597.7726698,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question_text": "What is Modus Tollens?",
        "answers": [
            "Affirming the antecedent: P -> Q AND P, thus Q.",
            "Inversion: P -> Q AND Q -> P, thus Q AND P.",
            "Denying the consequent: P -> Q AND ~Q, thus ~P."
        ],
        "answer": "Denying the consequent: P -> Q AND ~Q, thus ~P.",
        "n_times_asked": 6,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 6,
        "last_asked": 1657115608.3848941,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "logic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question_text": "When is a result statistically significant?",
        "answers": [
            "When it happens more than 50% of the time.",
            "When a result is confirmed independently by several sources.",
            "When it is unlikely that a result would have occurred under the null hypothesis, as defined by the p-value."
        ],
        "answer": "When it is unlikely that a result would have occurred under the null hypothesis, as defined by the p-value.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657115671.6931617,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question_text": "What is the Procrustean Bed?",
        "answers": [
            "A river bed that leads to the ocean.",
            "A bed made from crustaceans.",
            "A bed where people must fit perfectly: chop off those too long, stretch those too short."
        ],
        "answer": "A bed where people must fit perfectly: chop off those too long, stretch those too short.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657115677.8410606,
        "skills": [
            501,
            601
        ],
        "tags": [
            "mythology",
            "bias"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question_text": "What are oversampling and undersampling?",
        "answers": [
            "A reason for rejecting a given dataset as valid.",
            "Forms of resampling to even out representation of majority and minority data to avoid incorrect conclusions based on an unbalanced dataset.",
            "When statisticians go out and collect more samples of one kind and fewer of another to enhance the dataset."
        ],
        "answer": "Forms of resampling to even out representation of majority and minority data to avoid incorrect conclusions based on an unbalanced dataset.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657115695.0958538,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "question_text": "If playing a game where you can earn $1 per pip on a single rolled die, and have to pay $3 per roll, what is the expected value and is it worth it to play in the long run?",
        "answers": [
            "ev = $3; neutral: the expected value minus the cost is $0.",
            "ev = $2.50; not worth it: the expected value minus the cost is -$0.5.",
            "ev = $3.50; worth it: the expected value minus the cost is $0.5."
        ],
        "answer": "ev = $3.50; worth it: the expected value minus the cost is $0.5.",
        "n_times_asked": 2,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 2,
        "last_asked": 1657116020.1155665,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "question_text": "What is the Gambler's Fallacy?",
        "answers": [
            "Believing in the fairness of casino games.",
            "Confusing independent events for dependent events.",
            "Not cashing out soon enough."
        ],
        "answer": "Confusing independent events for dependent events.",
        "n_times_asked": 2,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 2,
        "last_asked": 1657116042.6412256,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question_text": "How are p-values (the threshold for statistical significance) determined?",
        "answers": [
            "It depends on the quantity of data available: more data means a higher threshold.",
            "They are arbitrary and decided by the researcher, but are often p = 0.05 or 5%.",
            "They are decided by the Statistics Bureau."
        ],
        "answer": "They are arbitrary and decided by the researcher, but are often p = 0.05 or 5%.",
        "n_times_asked": 5,
        "n_times_answered_correctly": 5,
        "last_asked": 1657116054.864761,
        "skills": [
            500
        ],
        "tags": [
            "math",
            "statistics",
            "data science"
        ]
    }
]
